# **AMOS AHINDUKHA**

056, Nairobi · +254743970626

amosmilimu@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/amos-ahindukha-089aa4221

I am an IT professional with over six years of experience in android and cross-platform app development, backend web development, front-end web development and project management. I am self-motivated, problem solver and always open to learning. My greatest strength is in Mobile application development a stack in which I have implemented several company and personal projects.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**DEC 2020 -**

# SENIOR SOTWARE DEVELOPER/PROJECT MANAGER, TOPIT INC.

In charge of the Topit flutter app development and Topit backend development.

MARCH 2020 - MARCH 2021

# LEAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, SIMBAPOS

In charge of SimbaPOS android app development and API development. Part-time.

JUNE 2018 - JAN 2021

# JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, MTEK

In charge of developing the MTEK client app, MTEK agent app, MTEK assessor.

JUNE 2018 - JAN 2021

# JUNIOR DEVELOPER INTERN, HILLCROFT

In charge of developing the Extreme Clean Flutter App. In charge of testing and fixing bugs in MTEK client app.

# **EDUCATION**

**AUG 2016 -- JUNE 2021** 

# BTECH INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF KENYA

Here I completed my bachelors of technology in information technology with a second class upper division.

Alongside my degree I was able to take short courses in IOT, AI, DATA SCIENCE and ANDROID APP DEVELOPMENT.

JUNE 2021 -- JUNE 2021

# FOUNDATIONS OF PROJECT MANAGEMENT,

GOOGLE CERTIFICATION COURSERA

I successfully completed this course with 94.04%.

JUNE 2021 -- JUNE 2021

# PROJECT INITIATION: STARTING A SUCCESSFUL PROJECT

## GOOGLE CERTIFICATION COURSERA

I successfully completed this course with 95.7%.

# **SKILLS**

## PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- Kotlin
- Java
- Python
- Typescript
- Dart

## **DATABASE**

- MySQl
- MongoDB
- ORACLE
- SQLite
- Firebase

#### **OPERATING SYSTEMS**

- Unix
- Linux
- Windows

## MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

- Native Android [Kotlin Java]
- Flutter [Dart]

#### WEB/BACKEND

- NodeJs
- Django
- Wordpress
- GraphQl API
- REST API

## **CLOUD**

- AWS
- Linode
- Digital Ocean

# **PROJECTS**

MTEK CLIENT APP

#### MTEK

# https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hillcroft.apps.mtek

Digital insurance app for purchasing insurance policies, making claims and comparing policies. Built in Java and Kotlin.

## EXTREME CLEAN APP

## **EXTREME CLEAN/MTEK**

# https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.app.extremecleanapp&hl=en

Mobile application build in flutter for car was booking, payments, subscriptions, bulk-buys and promotions.

MTEK AGENT APP.

## MTEK

# https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.app.mtekagent&hl=en

Native android application for insurance agents to sell insurance and interact with their clients. Built in Java and Kotlin

HAD POINT OF SALE APP.

# **PERSONAL**

# https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pointofsale.hadpos

A native android point of sale application build in Java and Kotlin. It enables users to make sales, manage users, manage inventory, view reports etc.

# **OTHERS PROJECTS**

- SAFARICOM DARAJA PAYMENT LIBRARY.
- DJANGO ONLINE STORE.
- SIMBAPOS POINT OF SALE APPLICATION.
- TOPIT SOCIAL MEDIA APPLICATION.

# **REFEREES**

## HENRY SHIKOLI

PRODUCT OWNER/ HEAD OF SALES SIMBAPOS

PHONE: +254726311988

EMAIL:HSHIKOLI@GMAIL.COM

# FELIX OKOTH

BOD/DIRECTOR ICT MTEK

PHONE: +254710705528

EMAIL:OTKOTH@GMAIL.COM

# RICHARD OMOKA

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER MTEK

PHONE: +254717225954

# **ACTIVITIES**

I have good interpersonal and communication skills. I enjoy learning from and teaching other colleagues for the general success of the organization and my personal skill enhancement. I am a good leader and a loyal follower.

I enjoy travelling, meeting new people in new places.